A Guide to the Records of Western State Hospital, 1825-2000
Library of Virginia
- Series II. Departmental and Program Records, 1942-1983., Extent: 24.5 cubic feet of records and 1 volume. cu. ft.
  - Series II., Subseries A. Community Hospital Industrial Rehabilitation Program (CHIRP) Records, 1962-1979.
    - Patients Credits, 1968-1970. (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Patients Credits, 1968-1970. (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Patients Credits, 1968-1970. (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Patients Credits, 1968-1970. (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - Patients Credits, 1968-1970. (Box 146, Folder 8)
    - Patients Credits, 1971. (Box 146, Folder 9)
    - Patients Credits, 1971-1972. (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Patients Credits, 1972. (Box 146, Folder 11)
    - Patients Credits, 1972-1973. (Box 146, Folder 12)
    - Progress Records, 1974-1975. (Box 146, Folder 13)
    - Recordkeeping System (CHIRP Workshop), 1972-1977. (Box 146, Folder 14)
    - Referral Instructions, 1974-1978. (Box 146, Folder 15)
    - Referrals Received, 1974-1978. (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - Referrals Rejected, 1976-1978. (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - Referrals Rejected, 1976-1978. (Box 147, Folder 3)
    - Referrals Rejected, 1976-1978. (Box 147, Folder 4)
    - Regulations (Administrative), 1975-1978. (Box 147, Folder 5)
    - Regulations (Director of Western State Hospital), 1968-1975. (Box 147, Folder 6)
    - Regulations (Director of Western State Hospital), 1976. (Box 147, Folder 7)
    - Regulations (Director of Western State Hospital), 1977-1978. (Box 147, Folder 8)
    - Regulations (Director of Work Programs), 1975-1978. (Box 147, Folder 9)
    - Regulations (Medical Services), 1974-1977. (Box 147, Folder 10)
    - Regulations (Department of Mental Health and Mental Retardation), 1973-1977. (Box 147, Folder 11)
    - Regulations (Department of Mental Health and Mental Retardation), 1973-1977. (Box 147, Folder 12)
    - Regulations (Patient Rights), 1975-1977. (Box 147, Folder 13)
    - Reports of the Work Programs Department, 1966-1967. (Box 147, Folder 14)
    - Report of the Work Programs Department, 1968. (Box 147, Folder 15)
    - Reports of the Work Programs Department, 1968. (Box 147, Folder 16)
    - Reports of the Work Programs Department, 1969. (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Reports of the Work Programs Department, 1970-1971. (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - Safety and Sanitation Inspections, 1970-1977. (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - Safety Committee Meeting Minutes, 1973-1978. (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook Material, 1962-1977. (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook Material, 1962-1977. (Box 148, Folder 6)
    - Sheltered Workshop Survey (U.S. Department of Labor), 1973. (Box 148, Folder 7)
    - Space (Square Footage), 1977. (Box 148, Folder 8)
    - Statistical Reports, 1979. (Box 148, Folder 9)
    - Statistical Reports, 1979. (Box 148, Folder 10)
    - Time Studies, 1978-1979. (Box 148, Folder 11)
    - Time Study Information, undated. (Box 148, Folder 12)
    - Valley Workshop, Inc., 1969-1979. (Box 148, Folder 13)
    - Vocational Rehabilitation Department, 1963-1972. (Box 148, Folder 14)
    - Vocational Rehabilitation Department, 1963-1972. (Box 148, Folder 15)
    - Work Assignments, 1969. (Box 148, Folder 16)
  - Series II., Subseries B. DeJarnette State Sanatorium Records, 1942-1947.
    Contains annual reports, brochures, and purchasing records of the DeJarnette State Sanatorium. The sanatorium was established as DeJarnette Sanatorium in 1932 by Western State Hospital superintendent Dr. Joseph S. DeJarnette. It functioned as a unit for voluntary patients with the financial means to pay for treatment. The sanatorium was a self-supporting institution, deriving its funds from patient payments instead of the state treasury. Dr. DeJarnette oversaw the operations of both Western State and DeJarnette Sanatorium until he resigned his position at the hospital and became the head of only the sanatorium in 1943. Dr. DeJarnette remained superintendent of the sanatorium until 1947, one year after the institution formally separated itself from Western State Hospital and began calling itself DeJarnette State Sanatorium. Researchers should note that correspondence regarding patients who resided at the sanatorium might be found in Series I. Administrative Records, Subseries D. Correspondence, Superintendent's Correspondence: Dr. J.S. DeJarnette. The DeJarnette State Sanatorium records are part of accession 41404.
    Arranged chronologically according to subject.
    - Annual Reports, 1942-1945. (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1946. (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Brochures, undated. (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Purchases, 1944-1947. (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Purchases, 1944-1947. (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Purchases, 1944-1947. (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Purchases, 1944-1947. (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Purchases, 1944-1947. (Box 149, Folder 8)
    - Purchases, 1944-1947. (Box 149, Folder 9)
    - Purchases, 1944-1947. (Box 149, Folder 10)
    - Purchases, 1944-1947. (Box 149, Folder 11)
    - Purchases, 1944-1947. (Box 149, Folder 12)
    - Purchases, 1944-1947. (Box 149, Folder 13)
  - Series II., Subseries C. Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (SGTC) Records, 1970-1983.
    Restricted: Documents containing patient names or information that are less than 125 years old. Some records may require review by an archivist and/or redaction (if it is possible) before they are served. Contains files correspondence, reports, and reference files created and utilized by the Director of the Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (SGTC), a semi-autonomous unit of Western State Hospital. The files include information on the specialized treatment of geriatric patients, the Intermediate Care Facility and Intensive Psychiatric Treatment certification processes, and the possible separation of SGTC from Western State Hospital. The files arrived in two separate accessions, comprised of five date-based subgroups: 1974-1978, 1978, 1979, 1981, and 1982. There is considerable overlap in dates and subject matter between the groups, so researchers should examine all of the subgroups for information on a particular person or topic. In order to better understand the files, it is necessary to provide background information on the leadership of Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (SGTC). Personnel changes were frequent during the years these files were kept, and job titles changed often as well. The records indicate that Lyn Harding served as Acting Director of SGTC from 1976-77, and then held the dual role of Assistant Director of SGTC and Assistant Director of Geriatric Services from 1977-1978. Later in 1978, Harding left Geriatric Services to become Associate Director, Administrative for Western State Hospital. As a result of Harding's departure, Paul Hundley, Director of Geriatric Psychological Services was named Acting Director of SGTC in 1979. Later in 1979, Phil Denton took over the dual roles Director of SGTC and Assistant Director, Geriatric Services, which he held until 1981. Early in 1981, Director Phil Denton resigned and Paul Hundley, Director of Geriatric Psychological Services, again became Acting Director. Hundley returned to his old position when Charles Spraker was appointed as Denton's permanent replacement in October 1981, and was still serving in this capacity in 1982. The Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center records are part of accessions 31704 and 32451.
    - "1974-1978" Director's Correspondence and Reference Files, 1974-1980.
      Contains files that appear to have created and maintained Lyn Harding, who served as Acting Director of SGTC from 1976-77, and then as Assistant Director from 1977-1978. Files of note include those devoted to the individual units, the work of the Health Systems Agency to promote better care for geriatric patients, program quarterly report information, and the files dealing with the possible separation of SGTC from Western State Hospital.
      Arranged alphabetically according to subject.
      - A-Unit, 1976-1978. (Box 157, Folder 1)
      - Blue Ridge Hospital Council, 1977-1978. (Box 157, Folder 2)
      - Breezeway, 1977. (Box 157, Folder 3)
      - Buildings and Grounds, 1977-1978. (Box 157, Folder 4)
      - B-Unit, 1976-1978. (Box 157, Folder 5)
      - Capital Outlay, 1976. (Box 157, Folder 6)
      - Catawba Hospital, 1976-1977. (Box 157, Folder 7)
      - Catawba Hospital, 1978. (Box 157, Folder 8)
      - Chaplaincy, 1977. (Box 157, Folder 9)
      - Chaplaincy, 1978. (Box 157, Folder 10)
      - Chapter X Board / Community Services Board, 1978. (Box 157, Folder 11)
      - Cleaning Agents and Procedures Committee Meeting Minutes, 1976-1977. (Box 157, Folder 12)
      - Community Hospital Industrial Rehabilitation Program (CHIRP), 1978. (Box 157, Folder 13)
      - Competence, 1976. (Box 157, Folder 14)
      - Confidentiality, 1978. (Box 157, Folder 15)
      - C-Unit, 1976-1978. (Box 157, Folder 16)
      - Day Treatment Task Force, 1977. (Box 157, Folder 17)
      - DeJarnette Center for Human Development, 1977. (Box 157, Folder 18)
      - Denton, Phil, 1978. (Box 157, Folder 19)
      - Departmental Instructions, 1976. (Box 157, Folder 20)
      - Discharge and Release Reports, 1976. (Box 157, Folder 21)
      - D-Unit, 1976-1977. (Box 157, Folder 22)
      - Environmental Beautification Committee, 1976-1977. (Box 157, Folder 23)
      - Equal Employment Opportunity, 1977-1978. (Box 157, Folder 24)
      - Erfe, Jose A. (Assistant Director, Clinical), 1974-1975. (Box 157, Folder 25)
      - E-Unit, 1977. (Box 157, Folder 26)
      - Feasibility Study, 1977. (Box 157, Folder 27)
      - Food Service, 1977-1978. (Box 157, Folder 28)
      - Forms Control, 1977. (Box 158, Folder 1)
      - Grey, William H., 1976-1977. (Box 158, Folder 2)
      - Grey, William H., 1978. (Box 158, Folder 3)
      - Grounds Privileges, 1978. (Box 158, Folder 4)
      - Hancock Geriatric Treatment Center, 1977. (Box 158, Folder 5)
      - Health, Department of, 1976-1978. (Box 158, Folder 6)
      - Health, Education and Welfare, Department of, 1978. (Box 158, Folder 7)
      - Health Systems Agency, 1977. (Box 158, Folder 8)
      - Health Systems Agency, 1977. (Box 158, Folder 9)
      - Health Systems Agency, 1978. (Box 158, Folder 10)
      - Housekeeping, 1976-1978. (Box 158, Folder 11)
      - Hyde, Robert T. (Assistant Director, Clinical), 1975. (Box 158, Folder 12)
      - Infection Control, 1977-1979. (Box 158, Folder 13)
      - Inservice Meeting Minutes, 1977. (Box 158, Folder 14)
      - Institutional Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1979. (Box 158, Folder 15)
      - Interstate Transfers, 1978. (Box 158, Folder 16)
      - I-Unit, 1977. (Box 158, Folder 17)
      - Jefferys, A.W. (Associate Director, Clinical Services), 1977-1978. (Box 158, Folder 18)
      - Job Descriptions, 1977. (Box 158, Folder 19)
      - Jones, Donald J. (Acting Director, Western State Hospital), 1977. (Box 158, Folder 20)
      - King's Daughters' Hospital, 1978. (Box 158, Folder 21)
      - Laundry / Linen, 1976-1979. (Box 158, Folder 22)
      - Legal Aid, 1977-1978. (Box 158, Folder 23)
      - Library, 1977-1978. (Box 158, Folder 24)
      - Medical Reviews, 1977. (Box 158, Folder 25)
      - Medicare / Medicaid, 1976. (Box 158, Folder 26)
      - Medicare / Medicaid, 1977-1978. (Box 158, Folder 27)
      - Medico-Legal Bulletin, 1978. (Box 158, Folder 28)
      - "Mental Health Services for Elderly Virginians" report, 1978. (Box 158, Folder 29)
      - Mental Health Workers, 1977. (Box 158, Folder 30)
      - "The Messenger," 1978. (Box 159, Folder 1)
      - Monthly Messenger Board Meeting Minutes, 1976-1977. (Box 159, Folder 2)
      - Monthly Messenger Board Meeting Minutes, 1977-1978. (Box 159, Folder 3)
      - Multilevel Interdisciplinary Care System, 1977. (Box 159, Folder 4)
      - News Articles, 1976. (Box 159, Folder 5)
      - Nurse Practitioner, 1976-1977. (Box 159, Folder 6)
      - Nurse Practitioner, 1977-1978. (Box 159, Folder 7)
      - Nursing Homes, 1977-1978. (Box 159, Folder 8)
      - Occupational Therapy, 1976-1977. (Box 159, Folder 9)
      - Organizational Charts, 1977. (Box 159, Folder 10)
      - Patient Abuse, 1977-1980. (Box 159, Folder 11)
      - Patient Advocates / Rights, 1978. (Box 159, Folder 12)
      - Patient Information, 1977. (Box 159, Folder 13)
      - Patient Records Example, 1974. (Box 159, Folder 14)
      - Patient Resident Population Reports, 1978. (Box 159, Folder 15)
      - Pettis Unit, 1977. (Box 159, Folder 16)
      - Pharmacy, 1977-1978. (Box 159, Folder 17)
      - Piedmont State Hospital, 1975-1977. (Box 159, Folder 18)
      - Plasberg, Coen (Western State Hospital Director), 1977-1978. (Box 159, Folder 19)
      - Plasberg, Coen (Western State Hospital Director), 1978. (Box 159, Folder 20)
      - Poterfield Geriatric Treatment Center, 1977-1978. (Box 159, Folder 21)
      - Problem Oriented Records (POR), 1977-1978. (Box 159, Folder 22)
      - Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center Development Committee, 1977-1978. (Box 159, Folder 23)
      - Program Quarterly Report, 1976. (Box 159, Folder 24)
      - Program Quarterly Report, 1978. (Box 160, Folder 1)
      - Program Quarterly Report (Draft Material), 1976. (Box 160, Folder 2)
      - Program Quarterly Report (Draft Material), 1977-1978. (Box 160, Folder 3)
      - Program Quarterly Report (Draft Material), 1977-1978. (Box 160, Folder 4)
      - Progress Notes, 1978. (Box 160, Folder 5)
      - Psychology-Social Work Inservice, 1977. (Box 160, Folder 6)
      - Receiving Unit Program, undated. (Box 160, Folder 7)
      - Recreation, 1976-1978. (Box 160, Folder 8)
      - Reorganization, 1977. (Box 160, Folder 9)
      - Right to Read, 1977. (Box 160, Folder 10)
      - Safety, 1977. (Box 160, Folder 11)
      - Safety Committee Meeting Minutes, 1977-1978. (Box 160, Folder 12)
      - Sanitation Inspections, 1976. (Box 160, Folder 13)
      - Sanitation Inspections, 1977-1978. (Box 160, Folder 14)
      - Security, 1978. (Box 160, Folder 15)
      - Semi-Annual Report, 1980. (Box 160, Folder 16)
      - Separation from Western State Hospital / Geriatric Planning Task Force, 1976-1978. (Box 160, Folder 17)
      - Sex Education, 1977. (Box 160, Folder 18)
      - Shenandoah Professional Standards Review, 1977-1978. (Box 160, Folder 19)
      - Southwestern State Hospital, 1977-1978. (Box 160, Folder 20)
      - Space Utilization Charts, undated. (Box 160, Folder 21)
      - Shenandoah Geriatric Staff Development Committee Meeting Minutes, 1977-1978. (Box 160, Folder 22)
      - Standing Orders, 1976-1978. (Box 160, Folder 23)
      - State Board Policy, 1977. (Box 160, Folder 24)
      - Stribling Building Coordinating Committee Meeting Minutes, 1976. (Box 160, Folder 25)
      - Swine Flu, 1976. (Box 160, Folder 26)
      - Task Force on Standards Development, 1977. (Box 160, Folder 27)
      - Task Force Report (Policies and Procedures), 1977. (Box 161, Folder 1)
      - Therapy Patrol, 1978. (Box 161, Folder 2)
      - Total Care Patients, 1977. (Box 161, Folder 3)
      - Unit Clerks Meeting Minutes, 1978. (Box 161, Folder 4)
      - Unit Meeting Minutes, 1976-1978. (Box 161, Folder 5)
      - Valley Mental Health Center, 1978. (Box 161, Folder 6)
      - Virginia Medical Assistance Program, 1977-1978. (Box 161, Folder 7)
      - Virginia Office on Aging, 1977. (Box 161, Folder 8)
      - Virginia, University of, 1978. (Box 161, Folder 9)
      - Visually Handicapped, 1977-1978. (Box 161, Folder 10)
      - Vocational Rehabilitation, 1977-1978. (Box 161, Folder 11)
      - Welfare Budget, 1977-1978. (Box 161, Folder 12)
      - Welfare, Department of, 1976-1978. (Box 161, Folder 13)
    - "1978" Director's Correspondence and Reference Files, 1974-1981.
      Contains files that appear to have been created and utilized by three men who held variously titled leadership positions during 1978, namely Lyn Harding, Paul Hundley, and Phil Denton. Files of note include those devoted to certification, both for SGTC to be an Intermediate Care Facility (ICF), and for Intensive Psychiatric Treatment (IPT) areas, as well as those folders containing information on patients' rights.
      - Activities, 1978-1980. (Box 162, Folder 1)
      - Activities, 1978-1980. (Box 162, Folder 2)
      - Activity Council Meeting Minutes, 1978-1980. (Box 162, Folder 3)
      - Beghtol, John (Assistant Director for Training and Community Affairs), 1977-1979. (Box 162, Folder 4)
      - Buildings and Grounds, 1976-1978. (Box 162, Folder 5)
      - Buildings and Grounds, 1978-1979. (Box 162, Folder 6)
      - Buildings and Grounds, 1979. (Box 162, Folder 7)
      - Buildings and Grounds--Wheelchair Ramp, 1976-1978. (Box 162, Folder 8)
      - Budget, 1977-1979. (Box 162, Folder 9)
      - Budget, 1979-1980. (Box 162, Folder 10)
      - Budget (1978-1980 Biennium), 1977-1978. (Box 162, Folder 11)
      - Budget (1978-1980 Biennium), 1977-1978. (Box 162, Folder 12)
      - Budget (1978-1980 Biennium), 1978-1979. (Box 162, Folder 13)
      - Budget Material, 1976-1977. (Box 162, Folder 14)
      - Budget--Personal Services, 1977-1979. (Box 162, Folder 15)
      - Budget Planning, 1977-1980. (Box 163, Folder 1)
      - Budget--Submitted, 1978-1980. (Box 163, Folder 2)
      - Cavey, Margaret (State Director, Geriatric Services), 1976-1977. (Box 163, Folder 3)
      - Cavey, Margaret (State Director, Geriatric Services), 1978. (Box 163, Folder 4)
      - Cavey, Margaret (State Director, Geriatric Services), 1978. (Box 163, Folder 5)
      - Cavey, Margaret (State Director, Geriatric Services), 1978-1979. (Box 163, Folder 6)
      - Census Track, 1976-1977. (Box 163, Folder 7)
      - Central Office, 1976-1977. (Box 163, Folder 8)
      - Central Office, 1978. (Box 163, Folder 9)
      - Central Office, 1978. (Box 163, Folder 10)
      - Central Office, 1978-1979. (Box 163, Folder 11)
      - Central Office, 1979. (Box 163, Folder 12)
      - Central Office, 1979. (Box 163, Folder 13)
      - Certification (ICF), 1975-1976. (Box 163, Folder 14)
      - Certification (ICF), 1976-1977. (Box 164, Folder 1)
      - Certification (ICF), 1977-1978. (Box 164, Folder 2)
      - Certification (ICF), 1978-1979. (Box 164, Folder 3)
      - Certification (IPT), 1974-1976. (Box 164, Folder 4)
      - Certification (IPT), 1977-1979. (Box 164, Folder 5)
      - Clerical Services, 1976-1980. (Box 164, Folder 6)
      - Community Adjustment Program, 1974-1977. (Box 164, Folder 7)
      - Educational Planning Committee (SGTC), 1979. (Box 164, Folder 8)
      - Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO), 1975-1976. (Box 164, Folder 9)
      - Equal Employment Opportunity, 1976-1977. (Box 164, Folder 10)
      - Equal Employment Opportunity, 1977. (Box 164, Folder 11)
      - Equal Employment Opportunity (Affirmative Action Plan Committee), 1976-1977. (Box 164, Folder 12)
      - Fiscal Department, 1977-1979. (Box 164, Folder 13)
      - Furniture Committee, 1978. (Box 164, Folder 14)
      - Hansen, Hobart G. (Director, Western State Hospital), 1976. (Box 164, Folder 15)
      - Harding, Lyn (Personal file), 1974-1978. (Box 164, Folder 16)
      - Kirven, Leo E. Jr. (Central Office), 1976. (Box 164, Folder 17)
      - Kirven, Leo E. Jr. (Central Office), 1976-1977. (Box 165, Folder 1)
      - Kirven, Leo E. Jr. (Central Office), 1977-1978. (Box 165, Folder 2)
      - Medical Care Evaluation Committee, 1976-1978. (Box 165, Folder 3)
      - Medical Care Evaluations, 1976-1977. (Box 165, Folder 4)
      - Medical Care Evaluations, 1977. (Box 165, Folder 5)
      - Medical Care Evaluations, 1978. (Box 165, Folder 6)
      - Medical Center, 1975-1977. (Box 165, Folder 7)
      - Medical Center, 1977-1978. (Box 165, Folder 8)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1976. (Box 165, Folder 9)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1977. (Box 165, Folder 10)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1977. (Box 165, Folder 11)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1977. (Box 165, Folder 12)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1978. (Box 165, Folder 13)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1978. (Box 165, Folder 14)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1978. (Box 165, Folder 15)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1978. (Box 166, Folder 1)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1979. (Box 166, Folder 2)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1979. (Box 166, Folder 3)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1979. (Box 166, Folder 4)
      - Medical Records / Statistics, 1979. (Box 166, Folder 5)
      - Medical Staff Meeting Minutes, 1979. (Box 166, Folder 6)
      - Medical Staff Meeting Minutes, 1979. (Box 166, Folder 7)
      - Meetings (Treatment Centers), 1976. (Box 166, Folder 8)
      - Nursing, 1976. (Box 166, Folder 9)
      - Nursing, 1977. (Box 166, Folder 10)
      - Nursing, 1978. (Box 166, Folder 11)
      - Nursing, 1979. (Box 166, Folder 12)
      - Nursing, 1979. (Box 166, Folder 13)
      - Patient Information, 1976. (Box 167, Folder 1)
      - Patient Information, 1977. (Box 167, Folder 2)
      - Patient Information, 1977-1978. (Box 167, Folder 3)
      - Patient Information, 1978. (Box 167, Folder 4)
      - Patient Information, 1978-1979. (Box 167, Folder 5)
      - Patient Information, 1979. (Box 167, Folder 6)
      - Patient Rights, 1973-1977. (Box 167, Folder 7)
      - Patient Rights, 1978-1979. (Box 167, Folder 8)
      - Patient Rights, undated. (Box 167, Folder 9)
      - Patients Under 65, 1977. (Box 167, Folder 10)
      - Patients Under 65, 1978. (Box 167, Folder 11)
      - Patients Under 65, 1979. (Box 167, Folder 12)
      - Personnel, 1974-1977. (Box 167, Folder 13)
      - Personnel, 1979. (Box 167, Folder 14)
      - Physicians, 1976-1978. (Box 168, Folder 1)
      - Physicians, 1978-1979. (Box 168, Folder 2)
      - Pre-Admission Screening, 1976-1979. (Box 168, Folder 3)
      - Pre-Admission Screening, 1979. (Box 168, Folder 4)
      - Recertifications, 1977-1979. (Box 168, Folder 5)
      - Reimbursement, 1976-1977. (Box 168, Folder 6)
      - Reimbursement, 1977-1978. (Box 168, Folder 7)
      - Reimbursement, 1978-1979. (Box 168, Folder 8)
      - Self-Care Evaluations, 1975. (Box 168, Folder 9)
      - Semi-Annual Report, 1979. (Box 168, Folder 10)
      - Semi-Annual Report, 1979. (Box 168, Folder 11)
      - Semi-Annual Report, 1979. (Box 168, Folder 12)
      - Semi-Annual Report, 1979. (Box 168, Folder 13)
      - Semi-Annual Report, 1979. (Box 169, Folder 1)
      - Social Services (Geriatric), 1977-1980. (Box 169, Folder 2)
      - Social Services Meeting Minutes, 1976-1979. (Box 169, Folder 3)
      - Social Services (Psychiatric), 1978-1979. (Box 169, Folder 4)
      - Social Workers, 1976-1977. (Box 169, Folder 5)
      - Training and Community Affairs, 1976-1977. (Box 169, Folder 6)
      - Training and Community Affairs, 1978. (Box 169, Folder 7)
      - Training and Community Affairs, 1979. (Box 169, Folder 8)
      - Training and Community Affairs, 1980-1981. (Box 169, Folder 9)
      - Unit Chiefs Meeting Minutes, 1977-1979. (Box 169, Folder 10)
      - Unit Departmental Meeting Minutes, 1976-1977. (Box 169, Folder 11)
      - Utilization Review Committee, 1976-1977. (Box 169, Folder 12)
      - Utilization Review Committee, 1978-1979. (Box 169, Folder 13)
      - Utilization Review Committee, 1979. (Box 169, Folder 14)
      - Utilization Review Committee Meeting Minutes, 1979. (Box 169, Folder 15)
      - Volunteer Services, 1976-1979. (Box 169, Folder 16)
    - "1979" Director's Correspondence and Reference Files, 1976-1982.
      Contains files that may have been created and utilized by Philip E. Denton during his tenure as Director of Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center from 1979-1981. Files of note include those devoted to Individualized Treatment Planning and changes to pre-admission screening processes.
      - Activities Council Meeting Minutes, 1979. (Box 170, Folder 1)